<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shawn Graham&#39;s Open Digital Humanities Notebook 2016-17</title>
    <description>An open history notebook forked from Jason Heppler</description>
    <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://smgprojects.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 12:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 12:17:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>notes on running the dh usb</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Our digital archaeology textbook will be intertwined with an instance of the DHBox. One of the participants in that project is Jonathan Reeve, who has been building a version that runs off a bootable USB. So naturally, I had to give it a spin. I ran out, got a new usb stick and….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…had to figure out Bittorrent. Every time I went to install the client, every browser I had on every machine kept blocking it as malicious. Normally I can work around this sort of thing, but it was really pernicious. Turned out, my stable of computers were all quite happy with uTorrent instead. With that installed, I grabbed the torrent files from the DH-USB repository, and let them do their magic. It took 3 hrs to get the full .img file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…had to figure out how to put that .img onto a usb stick such that it would be bootable. Unetbootin should’ve worked, but didn’t. In the end, I had to do it from the command line, per the ‘alternative instructions’:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MacOS: Identify the label of your USB drive with the command diskutil list. Then unmount the disk with diskutil unmountDisk /dev/diskX, replacing diskX with your drive name. Finally, run sudo dd if=/path/to/dh-usb.img of=/dev/rdiskX bs=1m again replacing /path/to/dh-usb.img with the path to the .img file, and diskX with the name of your disk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I had to figure out how to get the damned machines to boot from the stick rather than their own hard drive. On the Mac, this was easy – just hold the alt key down while the machine powers up, and you can then select the usb stick. NB: you can also, it seems, select whatever wifi network happens to be in the air at this stage, but if you do this (I did) everything will go sproing shortly thereafter and the stick won’t boot. So don’t do this. On the Windows 10 machine I had access to, booting up from a disk or stick is no longer the straight-forward ‘hold down f11’ or whatever anymore. No, you have to search for the ‘advanced startup’ options, and then find the boot from disk option, where  you specify the usb stick. THEN the machine powers down and up again… and will tell you that the security settings won’t let you proceed any further. Apparently, there’s a setting somewhere in the BIOS that you have to switch, but as it wasn’t my machine and I’d had enough, I abandoned it. Windows folks, godspeed. (Incidentally, for various reasons, computers much older than about five years are out of luck, as some key pieces of ur-code have changed in recent years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[you need] a modern system that supports UEFI. Legacy BIOS boot may be possible, but it hasn’t been extensively tested&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some other issues subsequent as I tried to install R and R Studio, but I’ve sorted those out with Jonathan and by the time you read this, they probably won’t be issues any more (but you can click on the ‘closed issues’ on the repo to see what my issues were). One thing that drove me nuts was trying to persuade Arch Linux to find the damned wifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually stumbled across this re ubuntu: https://help.ubuntu.com/community/WifiDocs/Driver/bcm43xx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so tried this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ lspci -vvnn | grep -A 9 Network&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and saw that I had kernal modules: brcmfmac, wl, but none in use. So I tried this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo modprobe brcmfmac&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and ran the first command again; kernal now in use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo wifi-menu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and connected. Kept getting connection errors; went to settings &amp;gt; network and connected through there, ta da!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/notes-on-running-the-dh-usb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/notes-on-running-the-dh-usb/</guid>
        
        <category>platforms</category>
        
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>tracery on glitch</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Lovecraftian archaeology via tracery.io [https://smgprojects.github.io/bots/traceryWeb/]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[http://glitch.com]. This site allows you to remix and deploy others’ code. So I rewrote the site report generator and moved it to Glitch; you can see it in action at [https://lovecraftian-archaeology.glitch.me/] and if you want to remix it go to the edit page. The key file you’ll want to edit is grammar.js . You could start by swapping in some of these examples but note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In grammar.js, you see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var grammar = {
        title : [&quot;Draft Report&quot;],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in that example gist I linked to, you see&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
&quot;origin&quot;: [&quot;I accuse #suspect# of committing the crime in the #room# with the #weapon#!&quot;],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grammar.js file does not put quotations around the key. So keep an eye out for that if you’re pasting from someone else’s project; paste from the opening { to the closing }. Also, origin is where the actual text will be generated from. So you compose your work by wrapping text around #keys# as in the second example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry. That’s a pretty awful explanation. Give the Tracery.io editor a spin to get the hang of it.  This is a really nice tutorial too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/tracery-on-glitch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/tracery-on-glitch/</guid>
        
        <category>tracery</category>
        
        <category>procedural generation</category>
        
        <category>glitch</category>
        
        
        <category>Experiments</category>
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>the workflow in this notebook</title>
        <description>&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-reminder&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-a-reminder&quot;&gt;A Reminder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-reminder&quot;&gt;A Reminder&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;terminal in the smgprojects folder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rake draft&lt;/code&gt; to create a new note in the drafts folder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rake write&lt;/code&gt; to open all notes in the draft folder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rake publish&lt;/code&gt; to move notes to the source folder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; to make the damned site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rake togithub&lt;/code&gt; to put the built site in the github repo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;push to github.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:39:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/the-workflow-in-this-notebook/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/the-workflow-in-this-notebook/</guid>
        
        <category>workflow</category>
        
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>running torch-rnn in docker on my mac</title>
        <description>&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#experimenting-with-a-recurrent-neural-network-package&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-experimenting-with-a-recurrent-neural-network-package&quot;&gt;experimenting with a recurrent neural network package&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-i-was-trying-to-do&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-i-was-trying-to-do&quot;&gt;what I was trying to do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-i-did&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-what-i-did&quot;&gt;what I did&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#things-that-were-hard&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-things-that-were-hard&quot;&gt;things that were hard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#thoughts-on-where-to-go-next&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-thoughts-on-where-to-go-next&quot;&gt;thoughts on where to go next&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;experimenting-with-a-recurrent-neural-network-package&quot;&gt;experimenting with a recurrent neural network package&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-was-trying-to-do&quot;&gt;what I was trying to do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was curious to figure out if I could train the computer to write an Indiana Jones script. To do this, you put together a file to show the computer what such a script looks like. This is the ‘training’ file, or the input.txt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I googled until I found the scripts. I used Raiders, Temple of Doom, and Last Crusade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading the documentation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karpathy/char-rnn&quot;&gt;char-rnn&lt;/a&gt; I realized that was too small, so I added Goonies and the Brendan Frasier Mummy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-did&quot;&gt;what I did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I followed the instructions at https://github.com/karpathy/char-rnn to download and install the char-rnn package&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the last instruction, about sourcing, I had to re-run when I logged back into dhbox&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;today’s history.txt file is &lt;a href=&quot;june21-todays-history-file.txt&quot;&gt;june21-todays-history-file.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-that-were-hard&quot;&gt;things that were hard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting the data. I went to gist.github.com and made a file, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/shawngraham/af1edaa5b40be09d643a4700bb2150af&quot;&gt;input.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I used curl to download it to the data folder, but had to find the ‘raw’ version, otherwise i just got the html that wraps the gist page. Raw version is behind the raw button on the page, [here](https://gist.githubusercontent.com/shawngraham/af1edaa5b40be09d643a4700bb2150af/raw/14c6a48715f20725256b9b2ccd13eeb3a3372fcd/input.txt]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;trained the rnn with this command: &lt;code&gt;th train.lua -data_dir data/input.txt -rnn_size 512 -num_layers 2 -dropout 0.5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;came back the next day, when it finished running (which is today). Had to enter the source command again before dhbox remembered where torch was installed - i cd’d into the torch folder to do that&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘sampled’ the model - this runs the generate-a-new-script thing &lt;code&gt;th sample.lua cv/some_checkpoint.t7 -gpuid -1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;had to ls the cv folder so I would know the file name for the last checkpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this printed the result to the screen; to do it to a file I added the &amp;gt; filename thing: &lt;code&gt;th sample.lua cv/some_checkpoint.t7 -gpuid -1 &amp;gt; script.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thoughts-on-where-to-go-next&quot;&gt;thoughts on where to go next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this ends the example. You could link to annotations you made, things you’ve seen, work that this entry is in dialog with, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note what is in this repo: a description of what I was up to; the results of my &lt;code&gt;$ history &amp;gt; todayshistory.txt&lt;/code&gt; command, the output of what I was trying to do, links to other things I used/created in the course of the experiment. You can make one repo with many folders, or many repos of just one folder, but whatever you do, try to keep everything together in a logical manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 11:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/running-torch-rnn-in-docker-on-my-mac/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/running-torch-rnn-in-docker-on-my-mac/</guid>
        
        <category>experiment</category>
        
        <category>rnn</category>
        
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>cradle</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Storytelling does a lot of work in ABM, although we don’t really acknowledge it as such. When you insert a player into the middle of an ABM, storytelling is your way of equipping the player with what she needs to know in order to survive, much like Sweeper tells Sam Vimes. So, I’m experimenting with Cradle which enables Twine and Twine-like storytelling within Unity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things to know about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/daterre/Cradle&quot;&gt;Cradle&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the last release is out of date, so don’t bother using it
download the repo, unzip, and use it to start a new Unity project (Start up unity, open a new project, and select the ‘cradle-master’ folder. Contrary to the readme, don’t try installing it in an existing Unity project yet. This is because the repo appears to be his actual project.
I kept getting an error in the logs concerning some error in one of the ‘test’ files. I can’t recall at the moment, and I can’t check because I’m at the wrong machine, so I’ll have to come back to this point. Commenting out the offending line solved the problem.
Drop your Twine file (twee or html) into the main Assets folder for your project. Cradle will convert that into C# for you.
Drag TwinePlayer prefab into the scene and then make sure to inspect it; add script to get it to point to your C# twine file.
Ta da.
Export as package, and select the relevant files (ie, you don’t need all of the assets or example game files etc) and then you can drag it into any other projects you have on the run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 11:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/cradle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/cradle/</guid>
        
        <category>archaeogaming</category>
        
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>tracery to write music</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;I came across this short piece by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codingblocks.net/videos/generating-music-in-javascript/&quot;&gt;Joe Zach&lt;/a&gt; where he uses tracery to generate a sequence of chords (the names of chords) which he then feeds into another library, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/scribbletune&quot;&gt;scribbletune&lt;/a&gt; to write those chords to a midi file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/shawngraham/mini-code-adventures-generate-music-with-js/blob/master/index.js&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a listen: https://soundcloud.com/shawn-graham-60451318/sand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking that this could be plumbed into a twitter bot somehow, write the midi overtop of an autoplaying video…? I dunno.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 11:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/tracery-to-write-music/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/tracery-to-write-music/</guid>
        
        <category>tracery</category>
        
        <category>procedural generation</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>Experiments</category>
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>writing with bookdown</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;For my current project, the Open Digital Archaeology Textbook Environment (ODATE for short; I’m rubbish at a) names and b) acronyms) Neha, Michael, Beth and I are trying to use Slack to manage our conversations, and writing instead in a series of markdown files, and use a repo to manage the collaboration, resolve conflicts, etc. Right now this is going swimmingly because for various reasons the rest of the gang can’t devote any time to this project. For my part, I’m trying to get the infrastructure and preliminary writing set up so we can hit the ground running in around mid march.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given our requirements outlined above, I looked around at a couple of different platforms, settling eventually on Bookdown . I like Bookdown because I can write in whatever editor strikes my fancy (switching into R to do the build) and it will give me a complete flat website (&lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; search), an epub, and a PDF, grabbing my citations from a Bibtext file and formatting appropriately (we have a collaborative Zotero library for adding to while we write/research; export to Bibtext, boom!). Right now, I’m writing within RStudio. With some minimal tweaking, it also allows me to build in Hypothes.is collaborative annotation (and via the Hypothesis API, I plan on collating annotations periodically to guid revisioning and also perhaps to build into the book user appendices, but that idea is still nebulous at the moment). I’ve also run the resulting website from Bookdown through various web accessibility tools, and the report comes back fairly positive. With some more tweaking, I think I can make the final product super-accessible, or at the very least, produce PDFs that screenreaders and so on can work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Bookdown set up was not without its idiosyncracies. The RStudio version has to be the preview release. Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;create a new project in RStudio (do this in a brand new folder)
run the following script to install Bookdown:
&lt;code&gt;
install.packages(&quot;devtools&quot;)
devtools::install_github(&quot;rstudio/bookdown&quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;create a new textfile with metadata that describe how the book will be built. The metadata is in a format called YAML (‘yet another markup language’) that uses keys and values that get passed into other parts of Bookdown:
&lt;code&gt;
title: &quot;The archaeology of spoons&quot;
author: &quot;Graham, Gupta, Carter, &amp;amp; Compton&quot;
date: &quot;July 1 2017&quot;
description: &quot;A book about cocleararchaeology.&quot;
github-repo: &quot;my-github-account/my-project&quot;
cover-image: &quot;images/cover.png&quot;
url: &#39;https\://my-domain-ex/my-project/&#39;
bibliography: myproject.bib
biblio-style: apa-like
link-citations: yes
&lt;/code&gt;
This is the only thing you need to have in this file, which is saved in the project folder as index.Rmd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write! We write the content of this book as text files, saving the parts in order. Each file should be numbered 01-introduction.Rmd, 02-a-history-of-spoons.Rmd, 03-the-spoons-of-site-x.Rmd and so on.
Build the book. With Bookdown installed, there will be a ‘Build Book’ button in the R Studio build pane. This will generate the static html files for the book, the pdf, and the epub. All of these will be found in a new folder in your project, &lt;code&gt;_book&lt;/code&gt;. There are many more customizations that can be done, but that is sufficient to get one started.
To get Hypothesis working, we have to modify the &lt;code&gt;_output.yml&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bookdown::gitbook:
  includes:
      in_header: hypothesis.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That html file is just a file with a single line, where you add the script src line for embedding hypothesis (see this guidance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You end up with a Gitbook-looking site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 11:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/writing-with-bookdown/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/writing-with-bookdown/</guid>
        
        <category>ODATE</category>
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
        <category>platform</category>
        
        <category>static site generator</category>
        
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>rehashing archaeology</title>
        <description>&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#rehashing-archaeology&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-rehashing-archaeology&quot;&gt;Rehashing Archaeology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#citations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-citations&quot;&gt;Citations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pivots&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-pivots&quot;&gt;Pivots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ok-so-how-do-you-do-this&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-ok-so-how-do-you-do-this&quot;&gt;Ok, so how do you do this?&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#examples-of-good-teaching&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-examples-of-good-teaching&quot;&gt;Examples of good teaching?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;slides: https://shawngraham.github.io/presentations/harvard.html  (resize your browser window a bit smaller, make it square, for best viewing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PGHFt-d9SCo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rehashing-archaeology&quot;&gt;Rehashing Archaeology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To rehash:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;v. To bring forth again in another form without significant alteration: &lt;em&gt;rehashing old ideas.&lt;/em&gt;
v. To discuss again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bit of a negative connotation there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked on twitter, as you do, what people thought I meant by ‘rehashing archaeology’, as I hadn’t figured it out yet. Titles first, thinking later, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stu: saying the same thing that has been said before but in a slightly different way to avoid plagiarism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ted: Fossilized hash browns. Or possibly HashMaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorna: rearranging what it stands for/means, away from current understanding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to discuss digital archaeology in all of these terms. Digital archaeology is nothing unless it gets rehashed. The problem is, how do you teach this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;citations&quot;&gt;Citations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with Stu’s thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confession – I google myself to see where my work is being cited. Numbers look good; this is a kind of reuse of my archaeological data, right? My studies are being cited, ergo the work I did is useful to someone else, ergo, it is being reused. But when you go deeper into this ‘reuse’, you find that it’s a surface-y reuse. Bit disappointing, really, to think your career is filler for someone else’s padding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That your entire life’s work is just an academic ‘required figure’, as Paul O’Donnel once put it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a topic model of 20 000 archae journal articles, from the 1930s to the 2010s, and no topic within it uses the words ‘reuse’ ‘reproducible’, ‘re-analyze’ in any meaningful way. ‘Data’ is prominent in two topics, but always new data. While we might ‘revisit’ an issue from time to time, no one is analyzing someone else’s data in any meaningful way in the broader noise of academia. Play with the topic models yourself at http://graeworks.net/digitalarchae/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody is rehashing archaeology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sobering thought. Part of the problem is packaging. We don’t play nice with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our heart of hearts, we don’t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; other people looking at our data. You see this in embryo when you try to force students to work together on a project. Re-using data is a group project where your group members live in the future, and you just &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; they’re going to be angry with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And will the data they play with be the data you left behind? How will they know?  Be on guard for deliberate alterations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[guard image]
—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me to make a tie in to Ted’s comment about hashmaps.
# hash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hash function takes any input and maps it to a particular value. It’s deterministic. If the input changes – say a text file gets edited and something gets deleted – the hash at the other end is changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is useful in security, to test that a message hasn’t been changed en-route; it’s useful for searching a database only for things that have changed; there are many useful things one can do with it. I direct you to wikipedia for more…
In the current attacks on rationality, knowing that our data has not been corrupted is going to become ever more important. We need to become familiar with hash functions in order to guard against malicious use of archaeology for political ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other uses for hash functions in archaeology, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my own work w/ Damien Huffer, we’ve been using Lincoln Mullen’s R package for detecting text-reuse via hash functions to trace patterns in the trade in human remains online (turns out, it’s a very useful signature for individual buyers and sellers’ writing patterns, even when there’s no id otherwise associated with the post. Be sure your sins will find you out.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but again, how do you teach archaeology students these things? it doesn’t ‘look’ like archaeology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which leads me to Lorna Richardson’s comment on digital archaeology perhaps being a pivot away from how we’ve done things in the past to how we might do things in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pivots&quot;&gt;Pivots&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorna’s research is extremely important for digital archaeology. One of the things she focuses on is what might be called the consumption side of archaeology within the web – of what is lately known as ‘fake news’ but formerly, ‘propaganda’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want people to engage with archaeology, right? Well, take a look at what’s happening on neo-nazi websites (I will not use the term alt-right.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people reuse archaeology, how do we teach them to do it correctly? How do we counter this? Are our current approaches to teaching archaeology &lt;em&gt;effective&lt;/em&gt; for the wider impact of archaeological knowledge in society?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand digital archaeology as necessarily a public archaeology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ok-so-how-do-you-do-this&quot;&gt;Ok, so how do you do this?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s return to the first problem, of surfacey reuse by academics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eric and I hatched a scheme last summer to promote re-use of materials in OpenContext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[img opencontext prize poster]
Incentives!, we thought, the good neoliberal dh-tools that we are. We offered real money – up to a $1000 in prizes. We promoted the hang out of it. We made films, we wrote tutorials, we contacted professors across the anglosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had very little uptake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[img tumbleweeds]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
## Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is not enough. But I wonder if part of the problem is that we’re dealing with a sunk-cost effect. So much of our computational archaeological infrastructure is proprietary software. Software, and databases, for which we’ve paid licensing fees. We’ve paid so much money, we damn well make sure that there is someone in our department, in our company, who can use Arcgis. Because this department, this company, uses ArcGis, it makes sense to teach that. But all this open source stuff? All these new formats? Who uses it? It’s a classic chicken-and-egg problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two other problems: there is no culture of undergraduate teaching with actual datasets ready to take advantage of the opportunity. Two, working with digital data still requires a level of digital literacy that we haven’t yet reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;examples-of-good-teaching&quot;&gt;Examples of good teaching?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at what the digital historians are doing: in particular, people like Lincoln Mullen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lincoln’s work builds capacity in others.
https://github.com/ropensci/historydata&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
Lincoln’s work is shared, and it’s explicitly about teaching how to use the materials he’s pulling together in his teaching&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://lincolnmullen.com/projects/worksheets/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
Lincoln addresses how to get your materials online in a format that others can then use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://lmullen.github.io/rmd-notebook/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
Ben Marwick, who is with you today, is doing this as well, and so as not to pre-empt him or otherwise get in his way, I’ll just tell you all to &lt;em&gt;listen to him very closely&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
## My own teaching fails&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hide in a history department these days, so I try to teach these things to my undergrads. First lesson I’ve learned is to never underestimate the social context of whom you’re trying to teach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety – my digital history students, if I can coax them through the door, are not in any way shape or form ‘naturally conversant’ with any of this. “If I wanted to do computers, I wouldn’t have taken history” said a student in one of my (officially non-dh) courses. “What if it breaks? What if it doesn’t work? How do I get an ‘a’?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear of Failure – we have not taught students how to fail productively. we have created systems where the risks of trying something different are usually catastrophic. Digital work requires the ‘screwmeneutical imperative’, as Ramsay famously put it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
Tech tutorials are &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; and I’m guilty of this as anyone: see http://workbook.craftingdigitalhistory.ca&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
Tech changes too rapidly, and the kinds of machines that students are sold are not necessarily the kind that can be usefully employed in this work. I’ve had students turn up to my dataviz DH course with nothing more than an iPad mini. I also end up spending two or three weeks solid getting everyone’s machine properly configured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom thinks I mostly do tech support. She’s mostly right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
# Ok, so what do we do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turn our teaching inside out. We do it in public. I’m not talking about MOOCs, though I suppose they have a role here, as educational tourism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I mean, we literally put all of our teaching out there and invite the public to take part alongside our formal students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we share with our students (and public) what has worked for us, and what hasn’t. we publish studies where the hypothesis didn’t work out. we replicate (with our students, and our public) someone else’s study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
this will be dangerous. you’re a white male? put that to use. get out there and take risks, and make it safe for others to do so too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
And it will require special tools. I’m building one right now with Neha Gupta, Michael Carter, and Beth Compton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
# ODATE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Digital Archaeology Textbook Environment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[img: DHBox + ProgrammingHistorian + Slack]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;funded by ecampusontario: thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
By building this, I’m trying to shift the infrastructure cost of learning to do digital archaeology from the student, from the individual, to myself. Build once, deploy everywhere as they used to say. To do digital archaeology should require only a browser. mitigate sunk costs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking our cue from OpenContext, we will include recipes for different kinds of tasks alongside the more formal learning activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to use ODATE for purely research purposes? No problem. Just use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything will be hashed properly so that you’ll know that, should you install it locally for yourself, you’ve got the true copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
What I need now are case studies. Data sets to work with. Reproducible research. Help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
Digital archae is an opportunity to rethink how we do things, to put a positive hash on rehashing the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—
This is what rehashing digital archaeology really means. we have to enable people to reuse our data for themselves, so at least the possibility will exist that they can see the truth of what is argued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rehashing is going to take a lot of work. But the results will be delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 12:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/rehashing-archaeology/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/rehashing-archaeology/</guid>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
        <category>re-use</category>
        
        
        <category>Essays</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>textreuse package for R</title>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Lincoln Mullen has a wonderful R package on rOpenSci for detecting and measuring text reuse in a corpus of material (the kind of thing that is enormously useful if you’re interested in 19th century print culture, for instance). [https://github.com/ropensci/textreuse] I wondered to myself what I would find if I fed it the corpus of material I’ve collected (see this gist) concerning the trade in human remains on Instagram (It’s looking for ngrams 5 words long, which means that I end up looking at 3k posts from my initial corpus of 13k). We’re writing all of this up for submission shortly, so this textreuse isn’t in our paper, yet; but anyway, a preview…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A score of ‘1’ indicates a perfect match. After running my materials through, I found many posts scoring 1. I thought, hmm, probably an error? Or perhaps, duplicate entries had found their way into my corpus? But after hand checking several I realized, no, the image is always different. So that’s interesting: people selling this material use the same language time and time again. Let’s consider some of it. We’ll start with this post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Real human skull for sale, message me for more info. #skull #skulls #skullforsale #humanskull #humanskullforsale #realhumanskull #realhumanskullforsale #curio #curiosity&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A post that scored 1 for similarity has the exact same text but a vastly different photograph. I’m not going to link to the photos or posts here because I don’t want to encourage this. A post at .9375 similarity has one extra hashtag appended to the text (and of course, a different photo):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Real human skull for sale, message me for more info. #skull #skulls #skullforsale #humanskull #humanskullforsale #realhumanskull #realhumanskullforsale #curio #curiosity #dead&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continue so on until we’re at arond .5 for our score:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Skull and arm £400 for the pair. One of the fingers on the hand is missing it’s tip and the whole arm needs glue removing and tidying up a bit. Real human skull for sale, message me for more info. #skull #skulls #skullforsale #humanskull #humanskullforsale #realhumanskull #realhumanskullforsale #curio #curiosity #dead&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These posts are all by the same individual. That one phrase, ‘Real human skull for sale, message me for more info’, and that sequence of hashtags is as good an identifier for this individual as any username I’m thinking. I’m still going through these results, but the thought occurs that perhaps I might find &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt; users using very similar language. If I found that, that would be very interesting indeed – a sign of influence between users? A sign of community? A kind of shibboleth, a marker of belonging?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other implications?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-r&quot;&gt;library(textreuse)
dir &amp;lt;- (&quot;posts&quot;, package = &quot;textreuse&quot;)
minhash &amp;lt;- minhash_generator(200, seed = 235)
ats &amp;lt;- TextReuseCorpus(dir = dir,
                       tokenizer = tokenize_ngrams, n = 5,
                       minhash_func = minhash)
buckets &amp;lt;- lsh(ats, bands = 50, progress = FALSE)
candidates &amp;lt;- lsh_candidates(buckets)
scores &amp;lt;- lsh_compare(candidates, ats, jaccard_similarity, progress = FALSE)
scores
write.csv(scores, file=&quot;textreusescores.csv&quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 12:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/textreuse-package-for-r/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/textreuse-package-for-r/</guid>
        
        <category>instagram</category>
        
        <category>R</category>
        
        
        <category>Code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ethics of video games in archaeology</title>
        <description>&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-playthrough-of-minecraft-as-an-archaeologist&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-a-playthrough-of-minecraft-as-an-archaeologist&quot;&gt;A Playthrough of Minecraft as an Archaeologist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#provocations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-provocations&quot;&gt;Provocations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Archaeology and video games share a number of affinities, not least of which because they are both procedurally generated. There is a method for field archaeology; follow the method, and you will have correctly excavated the site/surveyed the landscape/recorded the standing remains/etc. These procedures contain within them various ways of looking at the world, and emphasize certain kinds of values over others, which is why it is possible to have a marxist archaeology, or a gendered archaeology, or so on. Thus, it also seems obvious to me that you can have an archaeology within video games (not to be confused with media archaeology, or an archaeology of video games). Just as you can have ethics of archaeology, you can have an ethics of video games. What is interesting for us in the present moment is how these ethical perspectives intersect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious starting point in a discussion of the digital ethics of video games insofar as they intersect with archaeological ethics is of course the depiction of ‘looting’ as a game mechanic. Looting happens in a variety of games as a way of enabling the player to improve his or her character’s abilities by the performance of an otherwise meaningless task in the game environment. In games that explicitly frame their narrative in a way that intersects with cultural heritage, this looting is demonstrably archaeological looting, in that the objects collected represent the actual material culture of an in-game culture (or more commonly, uses a ‘real-world’ object as the model for the in-game object). Thus, the depiction of looting in games can be seen to normalize the activity of looting in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is true, and is a serious issue. But the ethical dimension of video games, especially as they pertain to archaeological ethics, goes much deeper. In what follows, I am heavily influenced by the work of Miguel Sicart (2009), who draws attention to two extremely important aspects that seem obvious but are actually rather subtle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 – that the player is an ethical agent in the world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 – that the game is both a designed object and a player experience in this world, and hence ethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In which case, ‘the experience of a computer game is the experience of a moral object by an ethical subject’ (5).  Too often, in discussions of video games, the player is depicted as some sort of secondary thing that is merely influence (ethically) by the game. But for Sicart, the player is an ethical creature and can make moral judgements about the experience within which she is immersed (11). So while a game that depicts unlawful acts – like looting – under a virtues-ethics perspective would be unethical, Sicart reminds us that this account does not take into account the player-agent’s ability to reflect on this (or indeed, to play in a manner that subverts it). A game that permits looting but also allows for such an act to have meaningful game play consequences for the player to act upon would be ethical, per Sicart (160). A game that permits looting, but has no meaningful consequences, is unethical (159). Sicart uses the example of Bioshock and the Little Sisters. Kill the Little Sister, and the player collects a certain amount of ‘Adam’ from the corpse, a valuable in-game resource; let the Little Sister live, and the Little Sister gives you very nearly the same amount of ‘Adam’ anyways. There is no in-game consequence, and for Sicart, this means that the game design is being unethical (160).  ‘A good computer game is that which fosters virtuous players, a game designed to create player-subjects who can understand and develop their ethical values, and where those values can be reflected. The player is responsible…’ (126). A game that features looting as a mechanic, from an archaeological perspective therefore, would be ethical if the consequences of that decision to loot gave the player a meaningful opportunity to decide whether or not to do so. It need not necessarily make the equation that looting = bad; but the consequences have to meaningful within the ludic narrative of the game so that the player can reflect on those consequences. We read novels to experience the world from another’s perspective – every decision within the novel is meaningful. So too should games be replete with opportunities for meaningful interactions and choices. The genius of Bioshock – where it is at its most ethical – is where it reveals at the end that the player never had any real choice in events anyway; that the designers have been puppet masters all along (163).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of Sicart’s ethics (the first being the subtle interplay between virtue ethics and the player’s own moral agency) is drawn from informational ethics (as he interprets the work of Floridi and Sanders). In this perspective, beings are data entities. Not all beings are biological. The materiality of a pawn in a game of chess is not what is important; rather it is in its relational situation on the board and the contingent interplay of that situation within the rules for movement for pawns (Sicart, quoting Floridi 2003). Data entities make meaning, or have meaning, in terms of their relationships with other data entities. Thus, data entities exist in an ecology of relationships – the Infosphere. The practical import of this is to extend agency to the game, or to objects within the game, and to situate them at the same level as the player agent. What constitutes an ‘agent’ in this perspective depends on how the Infosphere is abstracted (128-130; see also Morgan 2009 where she argues that non-player characters are non-human manifestations of a network of computation). Informational ethics sounds rather similar, to the archaeological ear, to ideas drawn from complexity theory or actor-network theory. Objects actually do want things (Gosden xxxxx).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Information ethics describes a moral universe in which not only is no being alone, but every being is indeed related, morally related to other beings, because in their well-being is connected the welfare of the whole system. Agents are systems that affect larger systems with their actions, affecting themselves as well, since other systems are procedurally and informationally related to them… Information ethics considers moral actions an information process’. (130). Emphasis in the original.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of considering the ethics of games from Sicart’s perspective is to explore an issue – like looting, for instance – and to situate it within the the web of interrelated elements and agents to develop a weighted network. While he does not mean an actual network-analytic approach to measuring things like centrality or degree within such a representation (he is more metaphorical than formal here), Sicart provides us with a way of operationalizing our ethical analysis of games. The locus of ethical responsibility within a game (whether it is with the player, the designers, the labor system, the market, the player community structure, the non-player characters, or what have you) can be read from this weighted  network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider for a moment the moral agency of the player.  Sicart points out games and their narrative layer, their ludic layer can be damaging to a player’s virtue when the player is not sufficient mature (201). That is to say, if we play games for which are own moral compass is not yet completely formed or developed, then these games can be a source of harm for the player. The obligation then rests on the game designer to create games where the ethical choices in the game have meaningful consequences. Then we as ethical agents ourselves can play the game to explore and probe the limits of our own ethical understandings (205). For archaeology, this means that our codes of archaeological ethics can be operationalized, made real and consequent, and testable in the sense that a player can begin to explore the consequences for herself.  Are our archaeological ethics deontological, rule-bound and duty-bound, and not necessarily meaningful for us as individual archaeologists? In which case, how do these intersect with the ethics of games as Sicart imagines them? A game should be a safe space to explore this contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This I think is one of the main avenues for exploration in the nascent area of ‘archaeogaming’. Instead of concerning ourselves with visual fidelity to an imagined past (for instance), we should actually be making games that embody our codes of archaeological ethics. When we play games as archaeologists (when we are consciously thinking as an archaeologists and using the morals and ethics of our profession) we should therefore be reflecting on what the game as a designed object is doing to how we think about the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what follows, I recount a play through of Minecraft, trying to behave as ‘archaeologically’ and ethically as I can. I then follow up with some more questions about where an ethically informed ‘archaeogaming’ might usefully proceed. When I write about video games, I am the player-subject I know best (and for whom I do not need to obtain ethics research board clearance). What are the web of weighted relationships in the games that I play most often? Are they ethical games? Am I an ethical player? How can we design games where the ethics of games (as described by Sicart) intersect with the ethics of archaeology?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-playthrough-of-minecraft-as-an-archaeologist&quot;&gt;A Playthrough of Minecraft as an Archaeologist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video games are simply the latest incarnation of humanity’s long history of creating virtual worlds. Whether the virtual world are the Caves of Lascaux, or the play-world of Hadrian’s Villa, one of humanity’s defining abilities is its ability to construct worlds removed from the everyday. What is perhaps unique about the current incarnation of virtual worlds is their accessibility: the ability for the virtual world I create to be shared with you; the ability for both of us to enjoy/explore/engage with that virtual world; the ability to be changed by that virtual world (provided that this virtual world is designed ethically: that is, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in its representation of a/the world, but rather in providing meaningful choices in how that world is experienced).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roger Travis has argued that the playing of video games bears deep affinities to epic oral tradition, that through play and reporting on what happened, we enter into a bardic mode of making meaning from the set pieces and action of games. Note that this is very similar to how Sicart defines the ethical player: one who has a mature reflection on the nature of the game; the moral presence of a player matters (Sicart, 201-2). For Travis, how those set pieces are encountered, in what order, and in what circumstances, are defined by the game’s mechanics and story – that is, its rules. The rules of a game encode the worldview of the game’s designers. You’re good at the game? You’re performing the worldview of the game’s creators (note again the way Bioshock plays with this at the end of that game). What’s interesting is the way the player’s moral compass, and her agency in the game intersects with those rules, and merges with the player’s own story, the story the player tells to make sense of the action within the world.  Play is the act of discovery. The story we tell about that play sits at the intersection between the player’s own agency, and the god-like agency of the game’s creators to specify the rules. What happens at this intersection is emergent, and if we examine that point, we will understand something of what it means to explore a game ethically; and to see that some ethical points of view are hard-coded and cannot be challenged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine then that Minecraft is a real place. After all, if I tell you that the seed I used in Minecraft 1.64 was Double Village with default biomes, you can travel to the exact same place that I visit, a parallel world in a multiverse that has suffered my interventions, but as of yet, not yours. What story shall you tell? Here is mine. I initially told it in a series of tweets, and so added another layer of performance to the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The texts all say the same thing. Set the portal to ‘Double Village’ and soon you’ll find the exotic and lost desert villages. I put on the archaeotrancerebretron, grabbed my kit bag, and gritted my teeth. My companions all had theirs on too. We stepped into the charmed circle…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…desert sand gives way to a compacted sedimentary stone. Is it natural? Or is it built? I had to stop myself &amp;amp; remember my training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… The next day we found the village. Much of it was above ground, including what looks to be the tower of a temple. We arrived on what appeared to be a market day. The locals go about their business, unconcerned about the ruined temple in their midst. No one stops us; but no one helps us either. Our ways are as alien to them as theirs to us; so long as they don’t get in way of Scientific Exploration!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered the temple, and began trying to record stratigraphically what I observed while I dug. The different kinds of blocks do help differentiate context – sand fill is quite different from the sandstone blocks the temple was built with. Unfortunately, sandstone is also part of the geology of Minecraft, and typically happens around 3 or 4 blocks down from the surface in this biome. So it became difficult to figure out where the temple ended and the local geology began. Since the temple is of a common ‘type’ in Minecraft (while the environment is procedurally generated and varied, the generated architecture conforms to a limited number of ideal-types),  and I was already familiar with it, I could just dig to exhume what I already believed to be there already: my ideas about the architecture of the place dictated what I would find. The act of excavation creates the archaeology in more ways than one, it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I dug, the sand shifted underneath me &amp;amp; I stumbled into the tower, breaking part of its friable decoration. “What do you see?” “…. beautiful things!” I replied&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly thereafter, an armed skeleton began firing arrows at me. But – in this world with no ‘rules’, no overarching ‘story’, deciding to go an an archaeological expedition forces a story on us.  Temples in Minecraft invariable contain ‘loot’, with booby-traps and revenants protecting it. Here, the influence of pulp fiction (and in particular, Indiana Jones) is clearly evident (the archaeologist-as-tomb-raider trope litters video games. The rules of interaction force me, an archaeologist trying to perform a facsimile of reasonable archaeological investigation, into the trope whether I liked it or not).  Killing the skeleton and looting the temple makes no meaningful difference in the story of the game, insofar as it gave me new materials to work with and to construct my own story. Given the Indiana Jones vibe, the moral action here is to kill the skeleton and obtain the material. After all, it “belongs in a museum!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s impossible, without seriously modifying the game, to excavate in anything other than a brute-force manner. While the NPCs will gather round to watch me work, they communicate with each other in an unintelligible murmur. As night falls, they respond to their own instincts and return to the village. They are Other. The information ethics that Sicart describes means that their agency within the game is as important as my own, and yet, my interaction with the NPCs, and the crude excavation tools that Minecraft gives me, pushes me towards a 19th century frame of mind, a colonialist discourse of ignoring as less important anyone who doesn’t look like me (one wonders at the consequence of this in other games, and in the wider demographics of game players). The archaeologist-as-better-class-of-looter trope seems to emerge naturally out of my interaction with the game mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Truly surprising. As night fell, gunshots rang out over this sleepy village on the desert’s edge. We set out to investigate. The villagers were congregated in a single home, discussing amongst themselves. ‘Let us in!’ we cried. We forced the door. Their conversation and shouts stopped. We all stared. The door was broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NPCs, responding to their own desires and needs, gather together inside a building to protect themselves against the game’s monsters, against whom they have no other defence. My desire to wander amongst them and my clumsiness at working the controls meant that I broke down the door. My decision to intrude – an ethical decision – has meaningful consequences for the other data entities in this game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘Back, men, to the camp!’ And we abandoned them to their fate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From above, I watched the zombies and creepers and who knows what else hunt each NPC down and kill them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Throughout the night, we heard their cries. Part of the men wanted to go help, the others huddled together in fear. As the sun rose upon my reentry to the village, I found no traces. It was as if the villagers had not existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My one attempt to engage the locals led to their annihilation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;provocations&quot;&gt;Provocations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will close with a list of provocations on the ethics of video games constructed or explored by archaeologists. I will offer no answers, but rather try to frame what I see as some of the more provocative ideas that are emerging around the idea of ‘archaeogaming’. If there is anything that truly defines ‘archaeogaming’ (see Dennis, Reinhard), then it must be the act of playing where the player’s ethical being is situated in the professional ethics of archaeology. Games do not have ‘ethics’ on their own, but their ethical nature emerges at the intersection of play and design. I expect to be wrong, to be challenged, and to be overcome. This too is in the nature of playing games: games challenge us, and provoke us, because they enhance or alter our abilities to inhabit another space, which is all the more reason to consider them ethically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provocation 1: Video games are built environments and thereby invite archaeological study. In which case professional archaeological ethics apply.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If video games are built places, and we are thinking like an archaeologist (as per Sicart’s ethically-informed player), then we have to treat them as we would any other site. Given that games are a designed experience and that they are part of an informational ethics, we also have to treat other data entities with the respect that our archaeological ethics accord them. How did my play conform to accepted ethical practice? How did it break it? What are the implications?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provocation 2: Games about the past/material culture exist in the world and draw their associations from the past and material culture of that world and so are entangled in the ethics of that world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a game draws on the artwork or the cultural heritage of a people in the ‘real-world’, the designers have an ethical obligation to consider how their instantiation of a looting mechanic (should they use it) has meaningful consequences in the game and for the people whose material culture is now being looted again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provocation 3: the ethics of making games are the ethics of labour, and power, and control.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The components that go into our electronics, that make game playing possible, are at the end of a long chain of exploitation, social and environmental damage. One need only think about the illegal and dangerous mining of rare earths in central Africa, the profits from which continue to support and prolong civil war and violence. Closer to home (as I write as a white North American academic comfortably ensconced in an ivory tower), labour laws permit exemption to number of hours of work per week in the special case of ‘information work’. If you make video games in Ontario, you can be made to work as many hours in a day as your employer desires.  Given this, should we, as ethically informed archaeologists, make games or play games at all? How do these conditions of exploitation and control of workers and resources square with our ethical codes of practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provocation 4: Performance and adherence to the rules of the game are an act of submission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Urrichio (2005) and Bogost (2007) convincingly argue that the mechanics and rules of a game can be thought of as the historiography of the game, the argument itself about the past that gets performed by playing a game. If we play games not as ethically informed archaeologists, if we do not write about games or critique games from an archaeological perspective, we are submitting to the power of the game publisher and the game maker to set the terms of reference about the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provocation 5 Modding and Fan Forums are an act of resistance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most ethical act we can perform as archaeologists confronting video games is to mod them. Very few of us have the skills, time, or safety to build and release a game from scratch. But we can use the tools of the commercial games themselves to literally reprogram their message, to add that ethical dimension of meaningful consequences, to confront games not just as designed objects but rather as a shared experience that can be ameliorated. We can and must be active in fan forums, Reddit threads, Twitch streams, Youtube ‘let’s play’ videos, blogs, journals, conferences, and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My final provocation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the ethics of archaeogaming are the ethics of digital public archaeology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 12:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://smgprojects.github.io/ethics-of-video-games-in-archaeology/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://smgprojects.github.io/ethics-of-video-games-in-archaeology/</guid>
        
        <category>archaeogaming</category>
        
        
        <category>Essays</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
